<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[ROBGRUNDEN]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[ROBGRUNDEN]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/robgrunden/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 04:12:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/robgrunden/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Infallibility & Inerrancy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Infallibility & Inerrancy</h1><p>The infallibility and inerrancy of Scripture are similar in that both deal with and defend the solidity of the central message of the missionary work of God in the Gospel while differing in the level of accuracy found in the details. It is feasible for a person to believe in the infallibility of the Word of God, while not believing in its inerrancy. However, we could not believe the Bible is inerrant without also believing it is infallible.

The term “infallible” finds its origins in the Latin infallibilis, with literally translates not-deceive. The idea as it applies to the Holy Scriptures, particularly as it is explained by Timothy Ward in his book Words of Life, speaks to the inability of the Bible to spiritually misdirect the reader. No matter a person’s belief about inerrancy, that the Word is infallible, simply put, means despite the possibility of small historical, cultural, and/or grammatical errors, the message doesn’t lie. The central message of both the Old and New Testament is, without doubt, the rescuing and redemption of the human race from and by the one true God that simply didn’t have to do it. To say the Bible is infallible means that no matter where you pick up in that grand theme and story the Scripture has no option but to not deceive.

When speaking of the Word as inerrant we are simply taking the issue of infallibility a step further. While infallibility deals mainly with the overall message inerrancy deals with that, as well as the minute details of history, culture and the like. If I said to you, “The Bible is inerrant”, to put it simply, I’m saying it is absolutely perfect and literally not errant or without error in any way. This means that every detail of scripture is historically absolutely accurate and the cultural concepts found in the Word are accurate beyond questioning.

Infallibility and inerrancy are definitely within the same family of thought. They both deal with the perfection of God’s Word, only they deal with different aspects of this perfection. Both unquestionably would agree, when it comes to God’s truth and his message to mankind, through the Holy Scripture, there are no mistakes, misuses, or misunderstandings. The message remains. The central truths about who God is, what He’s done, who that make us, and what we must do in light of that are perfectly clear and ready for study, conviction, repentance, and life-style change!</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/robgrunden/infallibility-and-inerrancy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e7506ed6-af37-44e2-912b-44839a2a55f2</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 04:11:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>This short paper is meant to inform the reader of the role of
the Trinity, particularly with regards to both the inspiration and ongoing work
of the Word of God. However, before we can jump into defining these roles, we
must first define what is meant by “inspiration” and “ongoing work”. These two
quick definitions will serve as foundational knowledge that must be understood
before discussing the individual roles of Father, Son, and Spirit.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/robgrunden/a3bad99f-5ca2-47a9-94d6-7a01fab6c874/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a3bad99f-5ca2-47a9-94d6-7a01fab6c874</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 21:06:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>